## Joseph Lawrance

Contact Information

550 Liberty St Apt 2202 Braintree, MA 02184

http://joeylawrance.com/ (541) 760-9374

Development Experience

Avid user of git, bash, R, and more.

Fluent in Java, Python, C and SQL; halting command of C++, Haskell, Perl, PHP, XSLT and others.

joey.lawrance@gmail.com

LinkedIn profile

Improved cWeed to deploy economic games to Mechanical Turk.

Developed an Eclipse plugin to collect programmer navigation data remotely.

Designed and implemented a system to integrate spreadsheet testing and fault-localization.

Wrote a parser combinator library in Java.

Wrote an extension to Java's grammar to support Perl regex syntax, using Parsec in Haskell.

Wrote Java and XSLT scripts to import web sites into MediaWiki.

Wrote a Sokoban puzzle game using SDL.

Wrote a Sudoku solver in Python.

Wrote an SVG viewer in C++.

Wrote a Japanese-English cross-language information retrieval system in Java using Apache Lucene.

Wrote foodservice scheduling software using Java Server Pages.

Wrote an Apache Coccoon-based live web-site rewriting system in XSLT.

Wrote compilers for Brainf— in Python, Java.

Wrote an XSLT script to produce XSLT diffs for XML documents.

Developed a web-based catering reservation system in Perl.

Wrote a turn-based trading game (Hiloto's Flowers) in C++.

Academic EXPERIENCE Taught undergraduate courses in C, Compilers, Computer Architecture, Data Structures, Humancomputer interaction, Java, Object-oriented programming, and Software Engineering.

Co-chaired PPIG 2010.

Co-authored over a dozen peer-reviewed publications.

Conducted a seven-month field study and two lab studies of professional programmers.

Created a predictive information foraging model of programmer navigation.

Conducted an experiment to examine how code coverage visualizations influence software testing.

Served on the Program Committee for DEFECTS 2008.

Started http://apiusability.org.

Mentored undergraduate researchers (Kyle Rector, Andrew Stucky, Nick Schultz, Mizuki Kagaya).

Tutored students in Calculus, Computer Science and Statistics.

Reviewed paper submissions for ACM CHI 2008-2012, IEEE ISI 2011-2012.

Gave invited talks at Harvard University, Brown University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Universidad Carlos III de Madrid, University of Nebraska-Lincoln, and Westfield State College.

Honors and AWARDS

AFOSR grant and NSF supplement from 2009-2012.

IBM Invention achievement award, 2009. IBM Ph.D. Scholarship, 2008-2009.

Best paper award honorable mention, ACM CHI 2008.

EMPLOYMENT

Assistant Professor, Wentworth Institute of Technology, Boston, MA. September 2010-Present Postdoctoral Associate, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, September 2009-August 2010 Research Assistant, Oregon State University. June-September 2004, June 2005-June 2009

Intern, IBM Research, Hawthorne, NY. June 2006-November 2008

Instructor, Oregon State University. June-August 2008

Teaching Assistant, Oregon State University. September-December 2004, March-June 2005

Intern, Microsoft. January-March 2005

Intern, American Airlines Federal Credit Union. June-September 2002, June-September 2003

Web Developer, Lawrence University, Appleton, WI. June-September 2001

Tutor, Lawrence University, Appleton, WI. April 2000-June 2003

EDUCATION

Ph.D., Computer Science, Oregon State University. 2009

Dissertation: Information foraging in debugging.

M.S., Computer Science, Oregon State University. 2005

Thesis: How well do professionals test with code coverage visualizations? An empirical study.

B.A., Math & Computer Science, Lawrence University, Appleton, WI. 2003

Minor: Psychology